{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "21st Century Literature",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "21st Reviewer Pro Max",
    "LastModified": "15 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "FIGURE-OF-SPEECH-Simile-and-Metaphor.pptx.pdf",
      "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What is 'a word or phrase used in a different way from its usual meaning in order to create a particular mental picture or effect'?",
      "answer": "Figure of Speech",
      "choices": [
        "Simile",
        "Metaphor",
        "Figure of Speech",
        "Comparison"
      ],
      "reference": "FIGURE-OF-SPEECH-Simile-and-Metaphor.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Figures of Speech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is 'an expression that uses words to mean something different from their ordinary meaning'?",
      "answer": "Figure of Speech",
      "choices": [
        "Metaphor",
        "Figure of Speech",
        "Simile",
        "Comparison"
      ],
      "reference": "FIGURE-OF-SPEECH-Simile-and-Metaphor.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Figures of Speech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is 'a figure of speech involving the comparison of one thing with another thing of a different kind'?",
      "answer": "Simile",
      "choices": [
        "Simile",
        "Figure of Speech",
        "Metaphor",
        "Comparison"
      ],
      "reference": "FIGURE-OF-SPEECH-Simile-and-Metaphor.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Figures of Speech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is 'used to make a description more emphatic or vivid, with the use of \"like or as\"'?",
      "answer": "Simile",
      "choices": [
        "Figure of Speech",
        "Simile",
        "Metaphor",
        "Comparison"
      ],
      "reference": "FIGURE-OF-SPEECH-Simile-and-Metaphor.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Figures of Speech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a figure of speech that 'describes an object or action in a way that isn't literally true but helps explain an idea or make a comparison'?",
      "answer": "Metaphor",
      "choices": [
        "Figure of Speech",
        "Simile",
        "Metaphor",
        "Comparison"
      ],
      "reference": "FIGURE-OF-SPEECH-Simile-and-Metaphor.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Figures of Speech"
    },
    {
      "question": "What came from the Latin word 'literatura' which means 'writing formed with letters'?",
      "answer": "Literature",
      "choices": [
        "Fiction",
        "Non-Fiction",
        "Literature",
        "Prose"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Literature Basics"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to artistic writings worthy of being remembered?",
      "answer": "Literature",
      "choices": [
        "Prose",
        "Fiction",
        "Literature",
        "Non-Fiction"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Literature Basics"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is it where the authors make up the entire story, they can choose to include information in a made-up story?",
      "answer": "Fiction",
      "choices": [
        "Non-Fiction",
        "Prose",
        "Fiction",
        "Literature"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Branches of Literature"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is also called 'informational materials', this type of literature provides information that is factual?",
      "answer": "Non-Fiction",
      "choices": [
        "Fiction",
        "Non-Fiction",
        "Prose",
        "Literature"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Branches of Literature"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a form of language which implies ordinary grammatical structure and natural flow of speech rather than rhythmic structure?",
      "answer": "Prose",
      "choices": [
        "Literature",
        "Non-Fiction",
        "Fiction",
        "Prose"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Literature"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a fictitious prose narrative of book length, typically representing character and action with some degree of realism?",
      "answer": "Novel",
      "choices": [
        "Short Story",
        "Play",
        "Novel",
        "Essay"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a story with a fully developed theme but significantly shorter and less elaborate than a novel?",
      "answer": "Short Story",
      "choices": [
        "Novel",
        "Short Story",
        "Play",
        "Legend"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a work of drama, usually consisting mostly of dialogue between characters and intended for theatrical performance rather than just reading?",
      "answer": "Plays",
      "choices": [
        "Novel",
        "Fable",
        "Plays",
        "Short Story"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a short piece of writing on a particular subject?",
      "answer": "Essay",
      "choices": [
        "Essay",
        "Biography",
        "Anecdote",
        "Myth"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a traditional story sometimes popularly regarded as historical but unauthenticated?",
      "answer": "Legends",
      "choices": [
        "Fables",
        "Myth",
        "Legends",
        "Anecdotes"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a short story, typically with animals as characters, conveying a moral?",
      "answer": "Fables",
      "choices": [
        "Legends",
        "Fables",
        "Myth",
        "Anecdotes"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a short amusing or interesting story about a real incident or person?",
      "answer": "Anecdotes",
      "choices": [
        "Myth",
        "Fables",
        "Legends",
        "Anecdotes"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a traditional story, especially one concerning the early history of a people or explaining some natural or social phenomenon and typically involving supernatural beings or events?",
      "answer": "Myth",
      "choices": [
        "Myth",
        "Fables",
        "Legends",
        "Anecdotes"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an account of someone's life written by someone else?",
      "answer": "Biography",
      "choices": [
        "News",
        "Essay",
        "Biography",
        "Novel"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is newly received or noteworthy information, especially about recent or important events?",
      "answer": "News",
      "choices": [
        "Biography",
        "Essay",
        "News",
        "Short Story"
      ],
      "reference": "21ST-REVIEWER-WEEK1.docx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Prose"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the composition of a person or any form in a work of fiction?",
      "answer": "Character",
      "choices": [
        "Dynamic/Round Character",
        "Flat Character",
        "Foil Character",
        "Character"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of character usually dynamically changes or transforms by the end of the story?",
      "answer": "Dynamic/Round Character",
      "choices": [
        "Flat Character",
        "Dynamic/Round Character",
        "Foil Character",
        "Static Character"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of character stays the same at the end of the story and is considered static?",
      "answer": "Flat Character",
      "choices": [
        "Dynamic/Round Character",
        "Flat Character",
        "Foil Character",
        "Round Character"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of character stands in contrast to another character, usually emphasizing a particular attribute of a more prominently characterized figure?",
      "answer": "Foil Character",
      "choices": [
        "Flat Character",
        "Dynamic/Round Character",
        "Foil Character",
        "Main Character"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is a Filipino poet, novelist, translator and literary scholar in Kinaray-a, Hiligaynon and Filipino?",
      "answer": "Genevieve L. Asenjo",
      "choices": [
        "Marcus Garvey",
        "Juan C. Laya",
        "Carlos Palanca",
        "Genevieve L. Asenjo"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Author's Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "Whose first novel, Lumbay ng Dila, received a citation for the Juan C. Laya Prize for Excellence in Fiction in a Philippine Language?",
      "answer": "Genevieve L. Asenjo",
      "choices": [
        "Genevieve L. Asenjo",
        "Marcus Garvey",
        "Carlos Palanca",
        "Juan C. Laya"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Author's Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is the author of \"PROMDI@MANILA\"?",
      "answer": "Genevieve L. Asenjo",
      "choices": [
        "Marcus Garvey",
        "Genevieve L. Asenjo",
        "Juan C. Laya",
        "Carlos Palanca"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Author's Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was named for the large black ants found on the island called \"hantik-hantik\"?",
      "answer": "Hantik",
      "choices": [
        "Antique",
        "Aklan",
        "Hantik",
        "Capiz"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Setting Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the capital of Antique?",
      "answer": "San Jose De Buenavista",
      "choices": [
        "Pandan Bay",
        "Belison",
        "Iloilo",
        "San Jose De Buenavista"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Setting Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the language of Antique?",
      "answer": "Kinaray-A",
      "choices": [
        "Hiligaynon",
        "Filipino",
        "Kinaray-A",
        "Hamtic"
      ],
      "reference": "W4-PROMDIMANILA.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Setting Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who has an MA in Creative Writing from UP Diliman?",
      "answer": "Exie Abola",
      "choices": [
        "William J. Bennett",
        "Carlos Palanca",
        "Exie Abola",
        "Alexis Abola"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Author's Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who currently teaches at the English Department at the Ateneo de Manila?",
      "answer": "Exie Abola",
      "choices": [
        "William J. Bennett",
        "Exie Abola",
        "Carlos Palanca",
        "Alexis Abola"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Author's Background"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is known as \"The Shoe Capital of the Philippines\"?",
      "answer": "Marikina City",
      "choices": [
        "Metro Manila",
        "Rizal",
        "Marikina City",
        "Bulacan"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Setting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where did the story \"Five Brothers, One Mother\" take place?",
      "answer": "Marikina City",
      "choices": [
        "Metro Manila",
        "Marikina City",
        "Rizal",
        "Bulacan"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Setting"
    },
    {
      "question": "What conflict is presented because they can't sleep without electricity and the mosquito was biting them?",
      "answer": "Man vs. Nature",
      "choices": [
        "Man vs. Self",
        "Man vs. Nature",
        "Man vs. Society",
        "Man vs. Man"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Elements"
    },
    {
      "question": "What conflict is presented because their mother start to get lonely as they grow up?",
      "answer": "Man vs. Self",
      "choices": [
        "Man vs. Nature",
        "Man vs. Man",
        "Man vs. Self",
        "Man vs. Society"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Elements"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the theme of the story \"Five Brothers, One Mother\"?",
      "answer": "Mother's Love",
      "choices": [
        "Sibling Rivalry",
        "Mother's Love",
        "Family Conflict",
        "Growing Up"
      ],
      "reference": "2.1-FIVE-BROTHERS-ONE-MOTHER (1).pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Literary Analysis"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the person or even non human creature in a work of fiction?",
      "answer": "Character/s",
      "choices": [
        "Protagonist",
        "Antagonist",
        "Character/s",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the characteristics of a person or any form?",
      "answer": "Character/s",
      "choices": [
        "Protagonist",
        "Antagonist",
        "Character/s",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the main character of the story?",
      "answer": "Protagonist",
      "choices": [
        "Antagonist",
        "Protagonist",
        "Foil Character",
        "Dynamic Character"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What opposes the main character?",
      "answer": "Antagonist",
      "choices": [
        "Protagonist",
        "Foil Character",
        "Antagonist",
        "Flat Character"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the characters that normally do not undergo changes throughout the story?",
      "answer": "Static or flat characters",
      "choices": [
        "Dynamic characters",
        "Foil characters",
        "Static or flat characters",
        "Protagonist"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the characters that are capable of undergoing changes?",
      "answer": "Dynamic characters",
      "choices": [
        "Static or flat characters",
        "Dynamic characters",
        "Foil characters",
        "Antagonist"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What stands in contrast with another character, usually the main characters - to highlight the protagonist's personality and qualities?",
      "answer": "Foil characters",
      "choices": [
        "Static or flat characters",
        "Dynamic characters",
        "Foil characters",
        "Antagonist"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Types of Characters"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the location of the plot, including the region, geography, climate, neighborhood, and interiors?",
      "answer": "Setting",
      "choices": [
        "Plot",
        "Climax",
        "Setting",
        "Theme"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the organized pattern or sequence of events that make up a story?",
      "answer": "Plot",
      "choices": [
        "Setting",
        "Plot",
        "Theme",
        "Climax"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the literary element that describes the structure of a story?",
      "answer": "Plot",
      "choices": [
        "Setting",
        "Theme",
        "Climax",
        "Plot"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the introduction to a story?",
      "answer": "Exposition",
      "choices": [
        "Conflict",
        "Climax",
        "Exposition",
        "Resolution"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is essential to the plot because if there's no conflict there would be no plot?",
      "answer": "Conflict",
      "choices": [
        "Exposition",
        "Conflict",
        "Climax",
        "Ending"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the struggle between two or more opposing forces which is the center of the plot?",
      "answer": "Conflict",
      "choices": [
        "Exposition",
        "Climax",
        "Conflict",
        "Resolution"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the point in the narrative where tension, excitement, or stakes reach the highest point?",
      "answer": "Climax",
      "choices": [
        "Conflict",
        "Resolution",
        "Climax",
        "Exposition"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the part of the story's plot structure where the conflict is RESOLVED?",
      "answer": "Resolution",
      "choices": [
        "Climax",
        "Resolution",
        "Exposition",
        "Conflict"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Plot Structure"
    },
    {
      "question": "What refers to the main idea of a story it conveys to its readers?",
      "answer": "Theme",
      "choices": [
        "Moral of the story",
        "Plot",
        "Theme",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the message, lesson, or insight that a story wants to tell to the reader?",
      "answer": "Moral of the story",
      "choices": [
        "Theme",
        "Plot",
        "Moral of the story",
        "Setting"
      ],
      "reference": "2-ELEMENTS-OF-THE-STORY.pptx.pdf",
      "term": "Elements of the Story"
    }
  ]
}